# **DYLAN COUZON**

San Francisco, CA 94103

Phone: (510) 513–9155 | Email: <u>dylancouzon@gmail.com</u>
LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/dcouzon</u> | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/Dylancouzon</u>
Portfolio: <u>https://dylancouzon.github.io/React-Portfolio</u>

#### SUMMARY

Ambitious, methodical, and resourceful Full-stack web developer with a penchant for blockchain technology. Curious by nature, passionate about puzzles and problem solving, coding has been a hobby for over 12 years. Previously working in UK, Australia, France, and now San Francisco has allowed for great versatility, adaptability, and an expanded cultural view of the user experience.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML | CSS | PHP | Javascript | Node.js | MySQL | NoSQL | GraphQL | Blockchain React | MERN Stack | ORMs | Linux | AWS | Microsoft Azure | Cybersecurity

### **PROJECTS**

# **Cryptonite** — Cryptocurrency application

https://bit.ly/2UcRdRG | https://github.com/Dylancouzon/Cryptonite | Jun 2021 Skills & Tools: HTML, CSS, MERN stack, Microsoft Azure

• Collaborated with a team of 4 in all phases of the development life cycle using SCRUM methodology

#### Personal contributions:

- Built, improved, secured, and maintained a centralized cryptocurrency
- Created all API endpoints allowing the Web app to communicate with the databases & Blockchain
- Set up a Linux virtual machine using Microsoft Azure to host the Web app, databases, and Blockchain

# **FarQuest** — Role-playing game

https://farquest.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/Dylancouzon/farQuest | May 2021 Skills & Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, MySQL

• Worked in a team of 3 to create the project in less than a week.

### Personal contributions:

- Developed the game outline: characters design, game mechanics, story writing
- Wrote from scratch the game mechanics (4200+ lines of code)
- Testing, debugging, and balancing difficulty

### **Feriale.fr** — Platform for an online game server

https://bit.ly/2WnrWoi | https://github.com/Dylancouzon/Feriale Feb 2010 - Nov 2012 Skills & Tools: HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, Javascript(jQuery.js), SOAP API

- Single-handedly created a Full-stack client interface allowing users to create an account, join the game, manage their account, and buy upgrades or additional items for their online characters
- Set up an admin interface allowing to communicate with the community and provide support to members
- Successfully maintained and kept improving the website for 2 years with over 99.7% uptime

### EXPERIENCE

### **Mademoiselle Colette Inc**, Newark, CA— *Production manager*

JAN 2020 - MAR 2021

- Managed the workflow of a team of 20+ people and training of new hires
- Ensured that all the products were up to company standard, meeting deadlines/customers expectations

# Citi Bank, London, United Kingdom—Pastry Chef

JAN 2018 - NOV 2019

- Managed the pastry production for 2 restaurants and an executive kitchen inside Citi Bank HQ
- Created bespoke menus for VIP customers

### **EDUCATION**

# UC Berkeley Extension, Berkeley— Jun 2021

Bootcamp Certificate -- A+ Academic average Intense Full Stack Web Development program in HTML/CSS, Git, JavaScript(jQuery, React,node), AJAX, MERN, SQL(MySQL, MongoDB)

### LANGUAGES

French: Native English: Fluent